novaragnarok.com 2019-06-03

# NovaRO

Our Privacy Policy explains what information we (NovaRO LLC) collect when you register an  
account with us and play NovaRO. Please read this Policy and the Terms of Use carefully  
before using our services in order to better understand why and how your data is used.  
Please note that this Policy only covers the NovaRO game server, website, and forums (the  
"Services"). This Policy does not apply to any third parties, such as Discord, Paypal,  
Facebook and Twitter, even when you use them to make payments to us or to interact with the  
NovaRO staff or community. 

**1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHY WE COLLECT IT**

a) E-mail and Username:  
In order to make use of the Services, you will need to provide us with your e-mail address  
and create a username, which will be used by us to verify your account (for example, in case  
you forget your password) and to send you important game related information, such as  
updates to this Policy and to the Terms of Use. 

You understand and agree that our access to your e-mail and creation of a username is  
necessary for the provision of the Services, and, as long as you keep an account with us, we  
will continue to store your e-mail address and username. 

b) Connection Logs:  
When you connected to the Services, we automatically store a connection log of your  
access, which will include your IP Address and your Hardware ID. This data may be used by  
us to keep your account secure and investigate any activity that may violate our Terms of  
Service, as well as to fulfill legal requirements in certain countries.  
You understand and agree that our storage of your connection logs is necessary to fulfill our  
legitimate interest of maintaining a safe and enjoyable game environment. 

c) Information You Send Through the Services:  
When you use certain functionalities of the Services, such as sending messages or creating  
a character, we will store the information you type. This data may be used by us to provide  
the Services (such as displaying your character name to players you interact with) and  
investigate any activity that may violate our [Terms of Service](https://www.novaragnarok.com/?module=main&action=terms). 

You agree to not include any personal information in your messages, character names,  
user names or display names while using the Services. You understand that, in view of the volume of  
information sent through our Services every day, it is impossible for us to monitor it for  
personal information which may have been sent by you in violation of this Policy, and if you  
do so you consent to our storage of such information. 

You understand and agree that our storage of the information you send is necessary for the  
provision of the Services and in light of our legitimate interest of maintaining a safe and  
enjoyable game environment. 

**2\. HOW WE STORE THE INFORMATION**  
The collected information will be stored securely on our hosting provider, OVH Hosting, in  
Canada, though we may opt to change our hosting provider at any time. By using our  
Services you agree to the storage of your information in Canada. 

**3\. WHO HAS ACCESS TO THE INFORMATION**  
The collected information will be accessed only by the NovaRO staff that require access to  
your information for the purposes described herein. We do not share your personal information  
with third parties. 

**4\. HOW LONG WE KEEP THE INFORMATION**  
We store your e-mail and username for as long as you keep an account with us. If you  
deactivate your account, we will remove your e-mail and username from our database.  
We store your connection logs for a period of 5 years. If you deactivate your account, we will  
generally delete your connection logs, except in case of any legal requirements mandating  
we keep those logs, or if we believe those logs are relevant to our investigation of rule  
breaking activity. In the first case, we will store the logs for as long as we are legally required  
to. In the second case, we will store the logs until our investigation is concluded and any  
penalties have been fully applied as per our Terms of Service. 

We store the information you send through the Services for a period of 5 years. Because this  
information is not considered personal information, and you agreed to not send any personal  
information through the Services, we will not delete this information if you terminate your  
account. 

**5\. YOUR RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS**  
You agree to always provide only correct and updated information during your use of the  
Services. Please note that due to security reasons, we do not allow your account e-mail to  
be changed, except in exceptional circumstances in the sole discretion of our staff.  
You have the right to download your information, which can be done through our Control  
Panel. 

You also have the right to withdraw consent and terminate your account with us, which  
can be done through our Control Panel. When you send an account termination request, for  
security reasons your account will be blocked for 14 days, and, after this period, you may  
request permanent deletion through the Control Panel. This is to prevent third parties from  
deleting your account, if they obtain your username and password. 

**6\. HOW TO CONTACT US**  
If you have any questions, requests or complaints regarding how we use your information,  
we can be contacted by e-mail at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#3051545d595e705e5f46514251575e51425f5b1e535f5d)

**YOUR CONSENT TO THIS POLICY**  
Please read this Policy carefully to understand it well before using the Services. By creating  
an account with us and clicking the "ACCEPT" button, you agree to the terms of this Policy.  
If you do not agree, you may not create an account with us. 

We may update this Policy at any time. When we do, we will alter the updated date at the top  
of this page and send a communication by e-mail. We recommend that users frequently  
check this page for any changes and to stay informed about how we are helping to protect  
the information we collect.
